

YEOH KAI SHENG IT ENGINEER

016-443-5934 ☎ yeoh4311@yahoo.com Air Itam, Penang 🙆

SUMMARY

Experienced IT engineer with 4 years of experience in semiconductor industry under CIM team and operation support team. Recognized for strong execution skills, commitment to quality work and a track record of delivering results in dynamic and challenging environments. Looking for better opportunity and career growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Engineer | 2022 - Present

TF AMD Microelectronics

- Team member of CIM team and Operation Support team.
- Responsible production and office systems releases in compliance with the Release Deployment Management process, delivered over >120 successful deployments to production
- Responsible of development and implementation of deployment and operation support tools to assist the team daily activities, successfully developed and implemented automated deployment tools that significantly streamlining the release process and reducing manual errors.
- Responsible of participate in 24/7 operational support, resolving production incidents and application-related issues, successfully resolved over 100 production incidents within SLA targets.
- Conducted User Acceptance Testing, performed root cause analysis, and validated solutions prior to production releases to ensure quality and compliance with business requirements.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams including developers, QA, infrastructure, and business stakeholders to coordinate seamless deployments and post-release support.
- Maintained and improved release documentation, and knowledge base articles to ensure team alignment and faster onboarding for new support team member.

IT Shift Support Lead | 2021 - 2022

MCSB Systems

- Outsourced to TF AMD Microelectronics as IT Shift Support and promoted to team lead at 2022.
- Lead daily operations during assigned shifts, including task assignment, ticket queue monitoring, and handling technical escalations.
- Managed and prioritized Jira tickets according to SLAs and team capacity, consistently achieving timely incident resolution.
- Coached and mentored team members to strengthen system knowledge and adaptability to frequent changes and new initiatives.
- Delivered daily updates on critical incidents, system status, and action items during stand-up meetings during daily IT stand-up meeting.
- Provided Level 2 support for over >300 production incidents, ensuring minimal disruption to manufacturing processes.
- Executed ad hoc tasks and special requests from other IT team and management to meet operational needs.
- Alert monitoring for servers, databases, and application to prevent any potential incidents.



YEOH KAI SHENG IT ENGINEER

016-443-5934 🕿

yeoh4311@yahoo.com ⊠

Air Itam, Penang 🙆

PROJECTS

DeploymentSQ 2.0

Automated CIM Deployment Tools - Visit me

- A CIM deployment management system designed to automate software rollouts, configuration updates, and version tracking across over >2000+ machines.
- · Results:
 - Reduced deployment errors by automating version control and rollback procedures.
 - Managed establish SECS/GEM communication with machines, ensuring smooth software updates.
 - Enhanced audit logging and deployment tracking for improved change management.
 - Reduced deployment errors by 99.9% through automated validation and improved rollout speed by >80% with streamlined workflows.

Tech Stack: ASP.NET Core MVC, C#, SQL Server

LReport

Web-Based Reporting Platform - Visit me

- A web-based reporting system to empower non-technical users to run pre-defined queries across multiple database with minimal technical support.
- Results:
 - Reduced engineering overhead by enabling self-service reporting for non-technical users.
 - Improved report delivery efficiency through scheduled email triggers.
 - · Centralized reporting across multiple systems with consistent user access management.

Tech Stack: ASP.NET Core MVC, C#, SQL Server

EDUCATION

BSc. (Hons) IT Business | 2019 - 2021

The University of Salford | CGPA 2.9

Diploma in Computer System Technology | 2016-2019

Sentral College Penang | CGPA 3.2 | Top Achiever Award | Best Student Award of 092016 DCST

CERTIFICATIONS

ISMS ISO 27001:2022 - Information Security Management Systems

TÜV NORD Group

SKILLS

Technical Skills: ASP.NET Core, .Net Framework, C#, Python, SQL, SECS/GEM, Javascript, OOP

Soft Skills: Fast Learner, Positive, Leadership, Problem-Solving